This is the solutions video for creating pet image labels.
本视频将讲解宠物图像标签的答案
First we need to define the get_pet_labels function.
首先 定义函数 get_pet_labels
The doc string indicates,
这里的文档字符串指出
we'll be inputting the parameter image_dir,
我们将输入参数 image_dir
which is just the path to the folder that contains all the pet images.
该参数其实就是包含着所有宠物图像的文件夹的路径
And we'll be returning petlabels_dic,
函数会返回字典 patlabels_dic
the dictionary that stores the image filename as the key,
该字典以图像文件名为键
with the pet image label as the value.
以宠物图像标签为值
In this function we first create the list, in files.
在函数中 我们先创建列表 in_files
That contains the filenames from the pet images folder.
列表包含 pet_images 文件夹中的所有文件名
Next, we create an empty dictionary petlabels_dic.
接着 创建一个空字典 petlabels_dic
That will be the dictionary we'll be returning from this function.
这就是函数会返回的字典了
We use a for loop to process all the filenames in the in files list,
我们用 for 循环来遍历列表 in_files 中的所有文件名
to create the pet image labels.
从而创建宠物图像标签
First there's the conditional statement that
在循环中 先用条件语句
skips processing all files that start with a dot.
跳过所有以 “.” 开头的文件
This should only occur if you're working on a Apple computer.
如果你用的是苹果电脑 那就要写上这个条件语句
If you're working in the lab work space,
如果你是在 lab 的 workspace 里进行操作
you won't need this conditional statement.
那就不需要写出
Next the image filename is split into a list of words based upon the under bar delimiter.
接着 根据下划线分隔符 将图像文件名分割成若干个词 做成列表
Image name is the variable that points to this list of words in memory.
变量 image_name 就是这个词列表在内存中的指针
Then we create the variable pet_label as an empty string.
接着 创建空字符串变量 pet_label
This variable will hold the pet image label that we've extracted from the filename.
该变量会储存从文件名中提取出来的宠物图像标签
Next we use a for loop to create the pet_label,
接着 用 for 循环创建 pet_label
by processing each word in image name.
循环会遍历 image_name 里的每个词
If the word is only made up of letters,
如果词只由字母组成
it's added to the pet_label as a string of
循环就会把这个词以字符串的形式添加到 pet_label 里
all lowercase letters with a blank space at the end.
设字符串为全小写 且末端各带一个空格
After the list of words is processed by extracting the words that only contain letters,
将词列表中仅含字母的词提取出来后
the trailing blank space is stripped off the pet_label,
把 pet_label 中跟在词后的空格删除掉
with the strip function.
删除用函数 strip 即可
At the end of the loop,
在循环末尾
the pet_label's added to the dictionary,
如果字典 petlabels_dic 还没有某个宠物标签
petlabels_dic, if it doesn't already exist in the dictionary.
那就把相应的 pet_label 添加进去
Where the dictionary key is the filename and the value is the pet image label.
字典以文件名为键 以宠物图像标签为值
Notice that a warning prints,
注意 如果字典里已有相应的文件名
if the filename already exists in the dictionary,
那就输出警告
because there shouldn't be duplicate filenames in the pet images folder.
因为 pet_images 文件夹不应有重复的文件名
Finally, we return the dictionary that contains the pet image labels.
最后 将包含着宠物图像标签的字典返回出来
Here we're at the function call for,
这里 我们在主函数中
get_pet_labels within the main function.
调用了函数 get_pet_labels
Notice we input in arg.dir.
注意输入的参数是 in_arg.dir
This is that command line argument that
也即指示图像所在文件夹
indicates what folder the images are located within.
的那个命令行参数
Where we're turning answers_dic,
调用后程序会返回字典 answers_dic
that dictionary that has the key,
该字典以文件名为键
the filename with the values,
以那些宠物图像标签
those pet image labels.
为值
Then we have here our temporary print statement,
这里的输出语句是临时的
where we check that we have 40 key-value pairs.
用于检查 40 个键值对有没有缺失
And then we check ten of those key-value pairs to make sure that we're
我们还要检查其中的 10 个键值对
processing those filenames appropriately to create those pet images label.
确保文件名得到了正确的处理 生成了相应的宠物图像标签
Let's look at the terminal,
我们来看终端窗口
where I've run the program, to check our code.
我已经运行好程序并检查好代码了
You can see I ran Python check_images.
你可以看到 我运行了 python check_images
We have 40 key-value pairs which we expect because we have 40 images.
如我们所料 总共有 40 个键值对 和实际相符
And then when we printed the first 10,
这下面输出了前十个键值对
we can see we've processed those filenames appropriately,
我们可以看到 文件名得到了正确的处理
or we've put the pet image labels in all lowercase letters.
所有宠物图像标签都以小写字母写出
There are spaces in between the words of those pet labels.
标签的词与词之间也有空格
And it seems like we've processed appropriately.
由此可见 操作无误